<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ModMetaData>
    <packageId>wishRobber.improveddefaults</packageId>
    <name>Improved Defaults</name>
    <author>wishRobber</author>
    <description>Tired of clicking through the same choices on every new RimWorld colony? Improved Defaults is a quality-of-life (QoL) mod that auto-configures the whole new-game setup - scenario, AI storyteller, difficulty, world generation, colonist policies and work priorities - to exactly how you like it, the instant each screen opens. Stop repeating yourself and start playing faster.

Every option stays fully editable; this only changes the starting selection. Nothing is forced.

What it presets:
- Scenario select: opens on Medieval Overhaul's "Battle Brothers", pre-selected and moved to the top of the list, instead of Crashlanded.
- AI storyteller: The Antagonist (falls back to Cassandra Classic if that storyteller mod is missing), with difficulty "Blood and dust", Reload anytime mode, and Anomaly incidents disabled.
- Create World: globe coverage, population, landmark density, pollution, a 325x325 map size, and a custom faction line-up.
- Colonist schedule: Recreation set at hours 6 and 21 on the default timetable.
- Hostility response: Attack instead of Flee.
- Self-tend: new pawns default to self-tend ON, so an injured pawn tends its own wounds instead of waiting on a doctor.
- Home-area toggles: automatic rebuild of destroyed home-area structures turned ON, and automatic home-area expansion around new constructions turned OFF.
- Carry / inventory stock: Healroot x3 for auto-medicine hauling.
- Reading policy: Tomes disabled in the default "Anything" policy.
- Food policy: a trimmed default "Lavish" - no rotten, human-meat or insect-meat food, with several categories switched off and sensible exceptions kept.
- Apparel policy: default "Anything" drops tainted apparel and the King's crown, and sets a 51-100% hit-points range.
- Work priorities: Manual priorities turned ON, with a full set of sensible per-colonist default priorities that scale with each pawn's passions (burning, interested, none).

Plus a Medieval Overhaul quality-of-life fix: silkworms are moved out of the food category and into Textiles, so colonists stop cooking and eating the silkworms you need to produce silk (silk production is unaffected).

Plays nicely with Prepare Carefully, Colony Manager Redux, FSF Complex Jobs, Vanilla Factions Expanded - Medieval 2, Medieval Overhaul and the Anomaly DLC. Every preset degrades gracefully - if a mod or DLC is missing, that piece simply no-ops.

Save-friendly: presets only apply to new games and newly created colonists, so existing saves are never touched. Lightweight Harmony patches on the setup screens and pawn initialization - no new items, no def bloat, safe to add mid-playthrough.</description>
    <supportedVersions>
        <li>1.6</li>
    </supportedVersions>
    <modDependencies>
        <li>
            <packageId>brrainz.harmony</packageId>
            <displayName>Harmony</displayName>
            <steamWorkshopUrl>steam://url/CommunityFilePage/2009463077</steamWorkshopUrl>
        </li>
        <li>
            <packageId>OskarPotocki.VFE.Medieval2</packageId>
            <displayName>Vanilla Factions Expanded - Medieval 2</displayName>
            <steamWorkshopUrl>steam://url/CommunityFilePage/3444347874</steamWorkshopUrl>
        </li>
        <li>
            <packageId>DankPyon.Medieval.Overhaul</packageId>
            <displayName>Medieval Overhaul</displayName>
            <steamWorkshopUrl>steam://url/CommunityFilePage/3219596926</steamWorkshopUrl>
        </li>
    </modDependencies>
    <loadAfter>
        <li>brrainz.harmony</li>
        <li>OskarPotocki.VFE.Medieval2</li>
        <li>DankPyon.Medieval.Overhaul</li>
        <li>wishRobber.theantagonist</li>
    </loadAfter>
</ModMetaData>
